Guide to the Francis C. Moon Reuleaux Reference Collection, 1841-2010
Moon, Francis C., Reuleaux Reference Collection
- Series I. Research
  - By Reuleaux
    - Reuleaux: Regulators, drawings, (n.d.) (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Copies of Reuleaux notes, drawings, etc. re regulators. Lots of drawings
    - Reuleaux: Gaskraftmaschine. Otto--Lungen., 1868 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Photocopy: Otto, H.A. and Eugen Langen. *Atmosphaerische Gaskraftmaschine.* Berlin: 1868. (G. Hickethier pub?) 1-13. Scribbled on front: von F. Reuleaux.
    - Reuleaux Plates, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Images of plates of Reuleaux mechanisms. One set labeled as being from "Theoretische Kinematik" (1875).
    - Chapter on Geradfuehrungen from Skizzenbuch der Angewandten Kinematik (1880), 1880 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      *Geradfuehrungen. In Skizzenbuch der angewandten Kinematik: Eine sammlung von mechanismen nach den Vortraegen des gehimen Regierungsrath Professor Reuleaux.* von den Studiernden der Kgl. technischen Hochschule. Berlin: Verein Huette, 1880.
    - Geradfuehrungen illustrations (Skizzenbuch), 1880 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Images/drawings of mechanisms
    - Reuleaux ed: "Einfuehrung in die Geschichte der Erfindungen", 1884 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Leipzig u. Berlin: Otto Spamer Verlag. Photocopy includes the forward and pages 523-582, chapters on Watt and the steam engine, and locomotives.
    - Reuleaux letters, notes and drawings, 1880s (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Photocopies of Reuleaux. letters to Thurston. 1880s. Also Reuleaux's lecture notes in German, and Reuleaux's hand drawings.
    - Reuleaux article, Muenzenmayer, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      "Franz Reuleaux: Kinematik--Aesthetik--Industrie. Konstruktion." 11. Bildnisse beruehmter Konstruktuere.
    - Reuleaux ed. technical dictionary (German-English), 1864 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      Dictionary of technical terms. From *Der Fuehrer des Maschinisten by E.F. Scholl,* "besorgt" by Reuleaux. Brauschweig: Friedrich Weiweg und Sohn. Pages 536-548
    - A.D. White, 1880's (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Photocopies and transcripts of Reuleaux letters to A.D. White. Photocopies of old articles.
    - Reuleaux sketches, 1870-1929 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      Photocopies of primary source material, including examples of Reuleaux's drawings
    - Reuleaux, F. Smithsonian, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Photocopy of a Reuleaux paper in translation: "Technology and Civilisation" (1890). Photocopies of other Reuleaux primary source material. Also, bibliography of writings on machines. Gathered in '99.
    - Cultur u. Technik--English, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      Copy of translation of Reuleaux: "The influence of the Technical Sciences upon General Culture" (trans Wheaton Kunhardt. From School of Mines Quarterly Vol VII No 1. Oct 1885). Looks like from DM.
    - Reuleaux's Die mechanischen Naturkraefte und deren Verwertung., 1901 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Photocopy of piece by Reuleaux. Berlin: Verlag von Hermann Paetel, 1901.
    - Cultur u. Technik--German, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      Photocopy of Reuleaux's *Cultur und Technik.* Wien: Verlag des Niederoesterreichischen Gewerbevereines, Druck von A. Keiss: 1884. Says: Vortrag Gehalten in Niederoesterrichischen Gewerbevereines.
    - Reauleux, Vol. II, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      Photocopy and some notes. "Lehrbuch der Kinematik von Prof. Dr. F. Reuleaux. Zweiter Band: Die Praktischen Beziehungen der Kinematik zu Geometrie und Mechanik" (Braunschwieg: Friedrich Vieweg und Sohn, 1900).
    - Reuleaux: On Style in Machine Design Translation, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      Photocopy of Rx's text in German: Ueber den Maschinenbaustil (Braunschweib: Fridrich Veiweg und Sohn, 1862). Summary in English (not a full translation).
    - Centennial Exhibition--Judges Letter. Reuleaux., 1877 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      Photocopy of letter (primary source).
  - Reuleaux biography and genealogy
    Includes research on Reuleaux’s biography and family. Genealogical material includes family trees and information on his ancestors and descendants.
    - Reuleaux Photos, (n.d.) (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Photocopied images of Reuleaux, Reuleaux-related landmarks, etc.
    - Redtenbacher booklet, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 44)
      From the Fakultaet fuer Maschinenbaue at the Karlsruhe Institute of Technology.
    - Correspondence: Reuleaux painting, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Correspondence about a portrait of Reuleaux
    - Dr. Henning Reuleaux, 1999-2004 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Notes, correspondence, online material for conversations with Henning Reuleaux and others, including Severin and Remberger.
    - Henning Reuleaux: Reuleaux family history, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      Includes a printed version of Henning Reuleaux fam history, plus a version on CD. Part 3 is on the Reuleaux family in the 1950's.
    - Reuleaux--Family History, 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Notes, a family tree narrative (in German), correspondence, photographs of models
    - Photos re Reuleaux and family, late 1990's or early 2000's (Box 2, Folder 49)
      Photos taken on Moon's trip to Berlin. Includes area where Reuleaux used to live, and Reuleaux relatives
    - Reuleaux at Stevens Tech, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      Reuleaux gave commencement address at Stevens Institute of Technology. This is a brief blurb about it in *Scientific American* (July 29, 1876. Vol XXV p 69).
    - Henning Reuleaux letter, re Reuleaux fam, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      Letter (in German) from Dr. Henning Reuleaux, about Reuleaux and his family.
    - Sylvia Reuleaux Pack, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      Correspondence with Reuleaux's great-granddaughter (American)
    - Sylvia Reuleaux visit 10-10, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Correspondence and notes re Sylvia Reuleaux Pack's visit to Ithaca.
    - Ahnentafel der Familie Reuleaux, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      Family tree for Reuleaux family, Berlin branch. With narrative/history in German. By Christian and Jo Reuleaux.
    - F. Reuleaux Photo: Spindle Collection, (n.d.) (Box 2, Folder 55)
      In da Vinci/Reuleaux book. Photocopied images of Reuleaux, one printed picture. Also includes photocopy of picture of Reuleaux. (One picture has him with his spindle collection).
    - Rx's house, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      Correspondence and an illustration, discussing the location of Rx's house in Berlin.
    - Reuleaux Grave in Berlin, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      Correspondence in German
    - Rx background, connections, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      articles, notes on Rx, esp. biography. Gathered 1999-2000
    - Marie Reuleaux, Reuleaux Who's Who, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      Info on Marie Reuleaux, list of people with Reuleaux connections.
    - De nakomelingschap van Antoon Reuleaux, (n.d.) (Box 7)
      Book and Reuleaux family material
- Series II. Models
  Contains information on kinematic models. These include models designed by Reuleaux and others, those housed at Cornell and those dispersed around the world. Also includes material on projects related to models, including the exhibit of Cornell’s Reuleaux collection and the KMODDL library.
  - Non-Cornell Reuleaux Models
    Information about models designed by Reuleaux, especially those housed at other institutions. Reuleaux designated Gustav Voigt and J. Schroeder to manufacture his models, and this subseries contains catalogs of the models Voigt and Schroeder sold. It also includes material on models designed by Reuleux’s mentor, Redtenbacher.
    - Reuleaux / Voigt Catalog / Koch catalog, 1912-1926. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Koch's catalog is from 1912 (physical catalog, not copied). Voigt's is mimeographed (1926 for the original?)
    - Schroeder catalog, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Voigt Catalog, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Another copy of the Voigt catalogs, 1 and 2nd Verzeichnis
    - Redtenbacher models, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Photocopies of drawings of Redtenbacher models
    - Redtenbacher models, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Correspondence and other documents related to Redtenbacher models
    - Reuleaux-Voigt Catalog, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Photocopy of catalog from 1907. Also includes color images of models (1999-2000)
    - German articles, Dresden models, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Photocopied articles on Rx model collections in Dresden. From Dr. FueBl, DM. Original copy from Dr. Mauersberger, Dresden, Oct 2001. From Sammlungen und Kunstbesitz der Technischen Universitaet Dresden
    - J. Schroeder--Darmstadt, VDI, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Photocopy of old catalog listing of models (German). Correspondence. Material on the Verein deutscher Ingenieure.
    - Schroeder Catalog, 1899 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Photocopy of model-maker J. Schroeder's catalog, with illustrations of models
    - J. Schroeder Catalog, 1884 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Selected photocopies from Schroeder's 1884 catalog.
    - Schroeder Model Catalog, 1884 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Photocopy of Schroeder's 1884 catalog.
    - Bovey, ASME, etc. McGill U. Models, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      Research related to the lost McGill models. Photocopies of McGill course catalog excerpts. Info on Henry T. Bovey.
    - Reuleaux E-mail: McGill U., 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      Correspondence and notes, trying to track down Rx models that used to be at McGill
    - Rx models: images, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 35)
      Printed photographs and other images of Rx models. Also includes some drawings.
    - Dresden / Hannover models, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      Info on other Rx model collections. Includes photocopied drawings, articles
    - Voigt Catalog--Translations, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      Photocopy of catalog, w/ translation notes in English.
    - Redtenbacher Models, Karlsruhe (Box 7)
      Copies of oversized drawings of Redtenbacher Models
    - Voigt Catalog of Reuleaux Models, (n.d.) (Box 7)
      Oversize photocopy of Kinematische Modelle Nach Professor Reuleaux. Also includes an undated original "zweites Verzeichness" of text.
    - Das Deutsche Museum: Geschicte, Aufgaben, Zielen, 1933 (Box 7)
      Book, info on Rx models
    - Kinematische Modelle Nach Professor Reuleaux publication, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Reuleaux Models at Cornell
    Records pertaining to the Reuleaux models obtained by Cornell president A.D. White in 1882. Includes material on the history of the collection and its use as a teaching tool. Also includes material on the permanent exhibit of the models in Duffield Hall, known as the Reuleaux Collection of Mechanisms and Machines, and designated a National Mechanical Engineering Historic Collection by the American Society of Mechanical Engineers History and Heritage Committee.
    - Reuleaux and Leonardo da Vinci Model Drawings by J. Hai, 2003 (Box 4)
      Drawings.
    - Old Mechanisms, from Jack Booker, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Photocopies of old Voigt catalogs. Includes actual book of Voigt models. Inventory of Cornell's collection.
    - Moon's 1999 report and Appendices, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Moon's 1999 report on the Rx collection at Cornell and appendices, including photocopied pages of cards describing the models from the 1940's or 1950's, and including a more current catalog.
    - Display Case Pictures, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Photographs, negatives, photocopies of images of Cornell Models. Also notes.
    - Cornell models correspondence and lists, 1987-1999 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Correpsondence, notes and lists for the models.
    - Bookpress: The Language of Invention, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Moon article on Cornell Rx collection
    - CU Model Inventory, 2004-2006 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Inventory, notes, catalogs
    - Inventory, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Inventory
    - KMODDL Inventory, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Inventory with images
    - Reuleaux Inventory, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Also includes relevant articles, including another copy of that Scientific American article.
    - Reuleaux Inventory, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Reuleaux exhibit photo, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Photo of Hunter Rawlings posing in front of the exhibit
    - Reuleaux "show and tell" model list, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      Moon's handwritten list of Rx models to show
    - Rx models: old pictures, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 24)
      Printed images of the old display of Rx models in Sibley
    - The Reuleaux Collection of Kinematic Mechanisms at Cornell University, official booklet, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Official booklet to accompany the Reuleaux Model exhibit.
    - Cornell Collection of Mechanisms and Machines: Reuleaux Kinematic Models brochure, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Brochure that predates the permanent exhibit, although it is undated.
    - Cornell Brochures on Reuleaux Model., (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Various brochures
    - Reuleaux Endowment Proposal, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Correspondence and proposals
    - Reuleaux Catalog: Model Descriptions, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      Descriptions of the models in Cornell's collections. Secondary stuff. Also includes notes. Two loose photographs.
    - Reuleaux/History/Cornell (No46), 1878-1894 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      Misc photocopies about the Rx models at Cornell.
    - Cornell College of Engineering Catalogs, 1924-1932 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Use of the RX models at Cornell: Architectural Drawing, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      Assignment revolving around the Rx collections, for Architectural Drawing 101
    - The Cornell Reuleaux Collection of Mechanisms, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      draft
    - Reuleaux: Report, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      Includes drafts and reports on Cornell's Rx Collection. Also includes photocopies of old cards describing the models, and memoranda. Photocopies of primary source articles.
    - Catalog of Rx Models at Cornell University, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      Also includes drafts, notes, etc.
    - Harvey N. Roehl: wrote cards on Rx Models (Box 3, Folder 41)
      Lived 1924-2000. Moon's correspondence with him. Includes copies of his index cards.
    - The Cornell Reuleaux Collection of Mechanisms, corrected copy, July, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      Another draft
    - Cornell magazine, Rx blurb, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      Entire magazine included. Blurb begins page 11. About Cornell's Rx models (quotes Moon).
    - Reuleaux Collection cards, (nd) (Box 3, Folder 44)
      Cards and photocopies of cards describing Rx's kinematic models at Cornell.
    - Cornell College of Engineering Catalogs, 1924-1932 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - School versus Shop: Cornell's Sibley College, (n.d) (Box 3, Folder 46)
      Photocopy of a book chapter by Monte A. Calvert in The Mechanical Engineer in America, 1830-1910. (n.d.) pp 87-105.
    - Sibley / Reuleaux, 1894; 1998 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      Photocopies from the Sibley Journal of Engineering (1894); a brochure on Hiram Sibley (1998)
    - ASME Heritage Nomination Rx, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Additional ASME Heritage Info, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Rx Models and Kids, (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 50)
      So cute--fan letters from kids about seeing the Rx collection. Also, materials from a scavenger hunt.
    - Cornell Kinematics Inventory, Helen Ng, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      Inventory and Notes
    - Reuleaux Collection: Curator, Endowment Notes, 2001-2004 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      Proposals, correspondence, notes, etc., all re Rx models at Cornell.
    - Duffield Display, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      [keep folder] Correspondence, notes, drawings, designs etc.
    - Lipson / Moon: Printing Rx in 3D, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 54)
      Articles, notes, drafts
    - Lipson / Moon: Printing History in 3D, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      Drafts, articles, drawings, a CD. Looks like the beginning of what became KMODDL, but I'm not sure
    - Rx ASME / Dedication, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      Draft of Moon speech, articles, fliers, etc. related to the dedication of the Rx exhibit.
    - Cornell Collection of Machines and Reuleaux Mechanisms correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Cornell Engineering - Reuleaux collection slides, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Double Slider and Ratchet, 2003-05 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - KMODDL
    Records pertaining to the creation of the Kinematic Models for Design Digital Library (KMODDL), an online library about kinematics and kinematic models, created by Moon and his collaborators at other institutions. It includes drafts of tutorials and essays for KMODDL, correspondence, and information regarding the National Science Foundation grant that originally funded the project.
    - Leonardo in Your Toothbrush Kinematics, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      KMODDL tutorial, written by Moon
    - Compound Mechanisms and Gruebler's Mobility Critereon, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      KMODDL tutorial by Moon
    - Beale F3, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 3)
      KMODDL bio written by Javier Lezaun.
    - Braithwaite--Spherical/Disc engine, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      John Braithwaite
    - Bramah N15, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 5)
      KMODDL bio for Joseph Bramah.
    - Bramer--Ellipisoidal, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Benjamin Bramer
    - Brauer W6, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 7)
      KMODDL bio for Brauer.
    - Cadiat T11, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 8)
      KMODDL bio for Nicholas Cadiat.
    - Cartwright S34, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 9)
      KMODDL bio for Edmund Cartwright, written by Javier Lezaun. Also includes other blurbs on Cartwright.
    - Chubb N13, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 10)
      KMODDL bio for Chubb Locks.
    - Dakeyne--Spherical/Disc Engine, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Edward and James Dakeyne
    - Dart I7, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 12)
      KMODDL bio for Joseph Dart and his elevator.
    - Davies F6, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 13)
      KMODDL bio forDavies/Davis.
    - Denison X3, X5, X6, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Notes on Edmund Beckett Denison, Lord Grimthorpe, and his clock-making. Includes additional blurbs on Denison.
    - Evans, S5, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 15)
      KMODDL bio for Oliver Evans and his mills and steam engines, by Javier Lezaun. Includes additional blurbs.
    - Farey--N24, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 16)
      KMODDL bio for John Farey, by Javier Lezaun.
    - Galloway I9, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 17)
      KMODDL bio for Elijah Galloway.
    - Graham X7, X8, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 18)
      KMODDL bio for George Graham, horologist.
    - Hooke P1, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 19)
      KMODDL bio for Robert Hooke, clock-maker
    - Jurgensen X10, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 20)
      KMODDL bio for Juergensen family of watch-makers
    - Koechlin Z2, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 21)
      KMODDL bio for Andre Koechlin.
    - Maudslay S33, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 22)
      KMODDL bio for Maudslay family of engineers.
    - Mudge--N20, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 23)
      KMODDL bio for Thomas Mudge, horologist
    - Oldham U1, 1916-2003 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      On John Oldham.
    - Pappenheim I1, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Pfitzer T6, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      Pfitzer brothers
    - Quintenz T9, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Reichenbach S22, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 28)
      KMODDL bio for Georg Reichenbach.
    - Redtenbacher T12, T13, 2003, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 29)
      Reuleaux's prof. Ferdinand Redtenbacher
    - Repsold I6, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 30)
      KMODDL bio for Repsold Family.
    - Roberts S14, 1917-2003 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Richard Roberts
    - Robertson Y12, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      John Robertson
    - Roberwal T8, 1917-2003 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      Gilles Personne de Roberval. Says Reuleaux probably meant him when he wrote "Roberwal"
    - Root I3, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 34)
      KMODDL info on "Root's blower." Notes written by Javier Lezaun.
    - Schoenemann T4, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      Theodor Schoenemann: nothing is known about him!
    - Schooeten--Episoidal, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      Frans van Schooten
    - Schwilgue T3, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 37)
      KMODDL bio for Jean-Baptiste Schwilgue.
    - Sellers Y1 Y2, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 38)
      KMODDL bio for Sellers.
    - Simpson and Shipton F1, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 39)
      KMODDL bio for Simpson and Shipton, rotary engine innovators.
    - Tschebischeff--S19, S 30, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      Referring to Pafnuty Lvovich Chebyshev.
    - Uhlhorn Z3, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      Diedrich Ulhorn
    - F5 Wedding, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      KMODDL bio for Hermann Wedding
    - Whitworth M5, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 43)
      KMODDL bio for Joseph Whitworth and the Whitworth thread.
    - Yale N14, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 44)
      KMODDL bio for the Yale family of lock-makers.
    - Biographical notes, misc, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 45)
      Misc biographical notes on Redtenbacher, Graham and others
    - KMODDL spreadsheet, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 46)
      KMODDL spreadsheet listing models, model numbers, and who writes what (bios, tutorials, etc.)
    - KMODDL Tutorial: Four-bar Linkage Coupler Curves..., 2003 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      Moon's tutorial: Four-bar Linkage Coupler Curves and the Roberts-Chebyshev Theorem
    - Compound Mechanisms and Gruebler's Mobility Criterion: Topological Invariants in Planar Linkages., 2005 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      A KMODDL tutorial written by Moon
    - KMODDL brochure, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 49)
      Photocopy of a KMODDL brochure: "Kinematic Models for Design Digital Library".
    - KMODDL Books: K Walker, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 50)
      Spreadsheets and correspondence re copyright permissions for digitizing books for KMODDL
    - Reuleaux / Digital Library, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      Correspondence about KMODDL, NSF
    - Digitized Books. KMODDL, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      Correspondence, catalog records, lists
    - C.U. Library and Artifact Collections, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      About KMODDL, also about preservation of the collection
    - Reuleaux--Library/Photo/Museum, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      Correspondence, lists
    - Reuleaux / NSF Proposal--J. Saylor, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      NSF Proposal. KMODDL Draft, corresponcence.
    - NSF Education Proposal, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      Proposal No. 0415374. Correspondence. Drafts
    - KMODDL Testimonials, 2002-2008 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      Correspondence (e-mails)
    - Assorted articles, Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Building a Digital Library of Mechanical Artifacts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - K-MODDL Phase 2, 2002-2006 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Assorted K-MODDL materials, 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Dartmouth Scientific Instrument Library Collection, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Institute of Museum and Library Services grant materials, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Institute of Museum and Library Services materials, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Grant proposals and summary, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - NSF grant proposal, 2004-01 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Other Models
    Information on models not designed by Reuleaux. Many of these model collections became a part of the KMODDL project.
    - Mechanical Contrivances, India, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      Photocopied article
    - Steam engine miniatures/models, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 59)
      Issue of *Mechanical Engineering*, vol 114 no 8 from August 1992. Article begins pg 34.
    - Misc Models, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 60)
      Images of models, drawings, etc.
    - Koch photos, (n.d.) (Box 4, Folder 61)
      2 photos of Peter Koch models
    - Peter Koch catalog (original), 1912 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      An original of a Peter Koch catalog of models. Includes illustrations
    - Ananthasuresh mechanisms, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 63)
      Drawings of models and material from Suresh G.K. Ananthasuresh
    - Mechanical models: Paris, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 64)